The cycles of fear and greed have
continued.
>> When people say altcoin Caesar is not
coming back this time, what would you
say to them?
>> They don't know what they're talking
about. So, Bitcoin that has two things
around it super cycle. Number one is the
fact that you only have 5% of people in
the world owning any Bitcoin and it
should like other disruptive
technologies that go mainstream
ultimately get to 70 80 90%. Even if
some of it's you know invisible to the
user, you don't go into the internet
these days and say, "Okay, let me make
sure I'm connecting to the TCP IP
layer." Right? It's all invisible and
that will happen with Bitcoin in the
currencies. The four-year cycles have
been remarkably predictive of
performance. So again, break each cycle
down into four seasons. So every cycle
has higher prices than the cycle before
it. Don't you talk about that in the
white paper?
>> Well, that just sounds too easy.
>> Is it really that easy?
>> So far, it's been.
>> Do you think institutions get into
Bitcoin changes this evenings?
>> I think this is considered to be the
start of the third super cycle for
commodities because of the the dollar. I
think the Satoshi planned it to be in US
presidential years and so far it's been
that way. But it was November of 2012,
July of 2016, May of 2020, April of
2024. At some point, if it keeps on
being less than 48 months, you're going
to have it be in the year prior to the
presidential election.
>> How would that change the cycle?
>> The last 40 years from 2100 to 2140 will
be a total of two and a half bitcoins
for 40 years.
>> Wow. I was not thinking about that. If
you can go in and figure out how to get
one Bitcoin over the next 10 years, I
think it'll be worth $20 million in, you
know, 20 years, 30 years. 2029 will be
the year after the next having. And I
think we'll be around half a million.
>> And then 2033 is I think we're going to
get a million. I think it's a given now
that we're going to be at a million
dollars.
[Music]
Where are we in the Bitcoin super cycle?
Where is this cycle headed and where
will it take the Bitcoin price next?
We're talking about this and many other
things with Michael Turpin, CEO and
founder of Transform Ventures. I'm David
Lynn
>> Bonnie Chang.
>> Michael, you've been referred to by
Legacy Media as the godfather of crypto.
Why?
>> Well, I guess I've been around a while.
Um, CNBC called me that in 2018. By then
I'd already worked on about 100 crypto
projects in terms of advising and
marketing. I helped um I founded Bit
Angels in uh early 2013, the first
investor group. We're in 30 cities now
uh including Las Vegas, including New
York, Dubai, Singapore, and it's uh
pretty decentralized. It's basically uh
each city um holds their own uh events
that connect founders with uh with
investors. And then we also do about 20
global events a year. So, for example,
we have a Denver chapter, but when ETH
Denver's in town, we roll in some global
resources because it it's obviously
going to be a bigger event.
>> What was your first crypto acquisition?
>> Bitcoin.
>> Mhm. All right. Well, we're going to
talk about the Bitcoin cycle.
>> Um, the Bitcoin super cycle. Um, you
said Bitcoin price has four seasons.
>> Yes.
>> Um, what season are we in now? And can
you break it down for us?
>> Sure. We are in summer, which is the
good season. Um, so Satoshi in the in
the white paper, and I talk about this
in the book, um, Satoshi in the white
paper said that as long as new Bitcoin
usage, you have to buy it to use it, um,
goes up more than the new Bitcoin that
are being mined, the price has to go up.
It never goes up in a straight line. And
that's where the Four Seasons comes in.
But every single cycle, we're in the
fifth cycle out of 33 now. And each
cycle has had fewer and fewer Bitcoins.
the very first cycle 2000 Genesis block
through the end of 2012 had 7200 Bitcoin
mined every day and um then after the
first having it got cut in half went to
in the second having third cycle went to
1,800. Four years later it went to 900.
Four years after that which is the cycle
we're in now fifth cycle after the
fourth having we're now at 450 per day.
Big change from 7200 a day. And to put
that in perspective, Michael Sailor buys
more than 450 Bitcoin a day. So Michael
and Micro Strategy alone take up all of
the Bitcoiner mind and they're certainly
not the only buyers. So as more and more
uh as they call them, Bitcoin treasury
companies emulate, you know, variations
of uh Micro Strategies model, as more
states and governments and eventually
countries um sovereign wealth funds
start buying Bitcoin. uh certainly in
the last year we've seen you know
institutions start buying it and also
the ETFs and the ETFs I mean Black
Rockck alone has more Bitcoin now than
Micro Strategy and it took Micro
Strategy almost five years to get what
they have and about a year for Black
Rockck.
>> Do you think institutions get into
Bitcoin changes the seasons?
>> Does not change the season. It just
simply changes the macro part. Right. So
um the math behind scarcity remains the
same. So we right now are this is the
first cycle that that new Bitcoin what
they call the stock toflow ratio is
scarcer than gold. So gold has
historically been about one to one and a
half sometimes as high as 2% of new gold
coming onto the market. So that's
through inflation
>> and it varies depending on the price of
gold. If the gold is high like it is
now, I mean, alltime high is $3500 or
so. Um, that means they have more
resources to go further down and, you
know, get some gold that wasn't viable
when it was, say, $200 an ounce. Not so
for Bitcoin. You can't go and put more
money into miners and ever increase that
amount of Bitcoin that comes out every
day. In fact, it's going to continue to
go down. So, right now, we're at 0.8 8
um inflation and gold is around 1.5. Um
in four years it'll go to 0.4 then 0.2
and literally the last um 40 years from
2100 to 2140 will be a total of two and
a half bitcoins for 40 years.
>> Wow. I was not thinking about that.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm just thinking you said strategy
alone buys more than 450 Bitcoin a day.
Correct. And all the big Bitcoin miners
are mostly hodling not you know
liquidating.
>> That's correct because they don't have
to liquidate because they have opt
resources.
>> So is it fair to say then that none of
the new bitcoins being created on a
daily basis are going to be available
for the public. So in other words in
practice the available supply is much
less than 21 million. It's what it
whatever it is now.
>> Well right now we're about to hit 20
million in the next couple of months.
>> Right. So that means that, you know,
we're about roughly 95% distributed um
in terms of like all the Bitcoin versus
what's left. So there's only 5% left to
mine. However, only 5% of the world has
any Bitcoin.
>> So at some point, you know, all
disruptive technologies tend to go
through this um technology adoption like
life cycle. They also call the S-curve
of adoption where the first, you know,
four, five, 6% take forever to get
going, right? That's when the early
people I mean it was written about in
crossing the chasm. It's been written
about in the Garper hype cycles. They're
all variations on the same um effect
which is that it takes 15 20 years to
get something to the point where it
really has the momentum to appeal to the
masses. And so you have the early
adopters that might take 15 20 years to
get going. Then you have the early
majority and that's a larger category. I
mean it's usually I think in you know
what Jeffrey Mor said I think it's about
3 4% that are the early adapters and
then it's maybe like 10 or 15% or the
early majority. Then you have the the
mid majority which is where you get to
like 50 60% of the population. You have
the late majority the lagards and then
you have people who never you know
there's still people don't own you know
a television but that's a very small
number of people.
>> Um can you tell us what indicators are
you looking at to tell you that we're
going from this season to the next?
First one is the calendar.
>> The calendar.
>> The calendar. So in other words, the
four-year cycles have been remarkably
predictive of performance. So I again
break each cycle down into four seasons.
So every cycle has higher prices than
the cycle before it. Satoshi talked
about that in the white paper that as
long as you end up having, you know,
more Bitcoin being bought than um
Bitcoin being uh mined, it has to go up.
It just doesn't go up in a straight
line. And this is where human fear and
greed come in. So after the having,
every single cycle, the price has been
flat and it's and it's the shortest
season. It's only four to seven months.
And the reason it's flat is because the
miners go from making money to losing
money in one day. And so if they're not
selling Bitcoin, uh some of them still
sell Bitcoin. And so
what happens is that you think the price
would drop if they're selling Bitcoin,
but there are other people who are
seeing where the cycles go and they're
like, "Okay, we just pass the having.
This is a good time to buy." And so
they're buying it up, but they're not
buying it up in a frenzy because they
haven't seen, you know, sort of the
tipping point of like the new bull
market. And so for example, this cycle,
you know, we hit Bitcoin summer the day
that it passed the all-time high of the
prior cycle. that was 73,850.
And uh what's interesting is most cycles
it hit the high for the whole four years
um at the end of the prior Bitcoin
summer. So that would have been 2021. So
we hit around 67,000 and change. And
what happened this year is we had an
anomaly because the pent-up demand for
the ETFs it got passed and all of a
sudden the month prior to the having you
end up having a new all-time high. That
was an anomaly. number of pundits said,
"Oh, that means the seasons are broken
or the cycles are broken." Or they said,
"Now we're going to have a short cycle
because this is the new all-time high
and so it'll be over within a year."
What they didn't realize, and I wrote
about this in the book, is that you
can't have this cycle's high before the
having. That's last cycle. The having
defines the break of the seasons, means
the cycles rather. And so that what that
did do was it marked a higher mark for
what you have to overcome to be a new
all-time high. So the 21 high of 20 67
we almost got there on the having. It
was like 60. It went down to the having.
And interestingly enough the having
price has been the perfect price of
Bitcoin. I call it the Goldilocks price.
It's not too hot, not too cold. If you
look in a rearview mirror, it is always
like it either comes down or comes up to
what the fair market price is when you
evaluate it later on in terms of like
you can clearly see the peak of the bull
market is is you know oversold and then
um or rather overbought and that the the
bare market a year later is oversold
>> and comes back to the middle
>> and so right the fair market value and
they can calculate that over time and
the having date has always been fair
market value. So it was fair market
value of $12 in 2012. It was fair market
value of $670 in 2016. It was fair
market value of $8700 in um the having
of 20 2000 2020 and it was 64,63,900
this last cycle. So you can see if
that's the fair market value every time
it's gone up quite a bit and but between
the cycles you have wild fluctuations
although less every cycle
after the first having well actually
before the first having you didn't have
a having you had the genesis block but
the difference between the first stated
price of a bitcoin sold which was one
sale it was 550 bitcoin it was sold on
PayPal for $5 that was Satoshi's intern
Marty Malcoly and um that was the only
sale for months and but that that that
counts as the first price of Bitcoin
onetenth of a penny. It went from
onetenth of a penny to $30 two years
later and then it crashed to a dollar.
And so that started kind of this
fluctuation between you literally went
from the first stated price of a Bitcoin
sale to the high of 3,000x and then it
crashed 97%. After the having having to
high first having was 100x and then the
pullback was 85%. Second second
havinging was 30x with 670 to 19,800 and
then pulled back 83%. And then third
having it went up should have gone up
10x because 3,130 the kind of path there
mathematically it should have been about
10x but we had bad macro. We had Biden
administration and Gary Gensler and you
know Elizabeth Warren trying to kill
everything and uh driving people out of
the US and sort of getting skittish
everywhere and you ended up having a
rapid rise in interest rates which you
know doesn't help for risk assets and so
instead of being 10x we were 8x I was on
a panel around the time and one of the
panelists said oh I think interest rates
are more important than having and I'm
thinking if that was the case then we'd
still be at $8,700
right and we're not. So it tamped it
down to do 8x. I think most active
classes would be very happy with 8x
right in a year. And so that's typically
what what happened the last time. And so
with that model I projecting that if we
keep along the same dynamic we'll be
about 3x. So 3x from the having puts us
at 193,000. Now that's with neutral
macro. If the bad macro of the economy,
tariffs are out of control, blah blah
blah, means that um it it it outweighs
the pro- crypto um you know, regulatory
that we have across all the forms of
government right now in the US. Um that
means the bad macro mean we'd be under
maybe as low as 150 160. Um if it was
more strong, we could go up another 20%.
So we could be like maybe 240. for much
over 250 I'd say that we started the
super cycle effect where you're
reversing the um diminishing returns.
>> I guess what I wanted to ask is how do
you determine the fair market value
>> each cycle?
>> Well the fair market value is sort of a
concept that I didn't invent. I mean
they they track that for stocks and
everything. You basically look at a
chart and you see you know what's
overvalued historically and what's
undervalued and when it comes back to
the median that's your fair market
value.
I um I did some math a long time ago. I
don't have the chart here. I was trying
to look for it on my phone. But if you
take the Fibonacci sequence 1 35, so on
and so forth. You plot that on a
logarithmic scale, it's a linear line
that goes 45°.
>> And if you plot the Bitcoin price chart
around that linear Fibonacci sequence,
it oscillates almost perfectly.
>> Y.
>> So this is the this is the fair value if
you want to take the Fibonacci sequence.
And it goes like this almost perfectly.
>> Fibonacci has been somewhat predictive
but not perfectly.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and um you know I I'd say that again
the calendar has been pretty damn
predictive because the highs of you know
there's 1384 days in a four-year cycle.
We aren't exactly 48 months. It's been
more like 46 months so far. But the high
has always been within a 37-day period.
That's like you know what 3% or
something like that. Yeah. of the of the
uh of the four years. Um it's basically
always been between the earliest it's
ever been is November 10th. The latest
it's been has been December 17th of the
year after the having.
>> Right.
>> Might move up a little earlier this
time, maybe October.
>> But within that period is that's when
you start watching and saying this is
probably when the bubble's going to pop.
>> I've heard people talk about the
four-year cycle before and the
counterargument has always been well
that just sounds too easy. Now, if
everybody believes in the cycle, we just
buy whenever there's a certain calendar
and then we sell whenever the certain
the calendar tells us to sell. Um, you
know, is it really that easy?
>> So far, it's been. And the thing is that
just because something is predictive and
keeps working doesn't mean everybody's
going to follow it or believe in it. Um,
sell in May and go away in the stock
market has been very reliable for 75
years. And when I was mainly a stock
market investor, I followed it. I sold
my whole portfolio in May. didn't have
to worry about it during the summer and
I and I would look to go and rebalance
in November.
>> That kept me all in cash during the 2008
crash. I didn't lose anything
>> and when November came around, the whole
world was still on fire and I said, you
know, I think wait a few more months and
so I was able to get, you know, my
portfolio back at a much lower cost
basis.
>> Could you talk about super cycle because
that term has been used a lot on
Twitter.
>> Yes. So super cycle has been used a
number of times over the years. I kind
of point out in the book the history of
it. Um, it was first called the Bitcoin
and Litecoin super cycle and then Dan
Held had talked about a super cycle
happening because of COVID and reaching
$800,000. Didn't quite happen. But to
me, I looked at the super cycle of where
the commodities uh super cycle has been
in effect. And this has been, you know,
established that there's been at least
three uh super cycles. So really you go
all the way back to uh the Elliot waves
and and the he actually talked about the
grand super cycle which lasted you know
sometimes like hundreds of years right
and that's that's sort of similar what
Ralph Dalio talks about about you know
empires you know every 500 years or so
and um so Elliot and Dalio and a number
of other people sort of identified these
big epochs and then within that you have
lower cycles um you know those 80year
cycles but a super cycle is usually a
period of more than five years. It can't
be a shorter period where there's a
fundamental change in the narrative that
drives um you know outsized
profitability. And so in the 70s gold
quadrupled and that was because of a
fundamental change in the narrative. Two
things happened. Number one, the US went
off the gold standard. And number two,
Americans were allowed to own gold again
and they had been prohibited since the
1930s. And so the new uh buyers coming
in, new demand as well as a reason to
not you know kind of trust the full
faith in the American dollar because it
was no longer backed by gold.
>> Um you know led to a very good strategy
and number of hedge funds made their
careers on that by quadrupling uh their
you know their money in in less than a
decade. In the 90s you had another super
cycle in the commodities market which is
based on China. So in other words, China
started buying everything and that upped
the price of nickel, copper, you name
it. And um this is considered to be the
start of a third super cycle for
commodities because of the the dollar
because of the the dollar, you know,
kind of going the way of the yen and
other places that just had too much
debt.
>> Are you familiar with Neil House fourth
turning?
>> Yes. So the theory is every well he's
looked at this and every 80 years
there's a major crisis and that's
because of generational shifts. We are
in that 80 80th year now give or take
the fourth turning is happening. How
would you evaluate that? How does that
fit into your super cycle thesis?
>> Well I mean I think that that's macro.
So in other words um
you know
Satoshi wrote the paper in 2008. his
reason for writing it was, you know,
sort of the reaction to the, you know,
the great recession as they call it. And
so, um, and then what you're seeing with
AI now, um, you know, which could
potentially disrupt everybody's
employment, uh, redefine it, you know,
similar to like where maybe 80 years ago
or 160 years ago, the coming of the
industrial age, coming of the
information age. I mean I think there's
been more disruption than just every 80
years but uh yeah the 80year phenomena
which depending on how you count it I
mean some people thought that was the
change of the 1920s to you know 2000
other ones are like 1940s to now so
>> you know I think there's a little bit of
fuzziness in that model in terms of when
it actually yeah uh turns
>> but um you know I think that uh that's
sort of that broader cycle within which
the so I'm just talking about Bitcoin
that has two things around its super
cycle. Number one is the fact that you
only have 5% of people in the world
owning any Bitcoin and it should like
other disruptive technologies that go
mainstream ultimately get to 70 80 90%.
even if some of it's you know invisible
to the user. I mean, you don't go online
anymore, which internet's like 90
something percent usage. Uh, if you
include internet through cell phones,
which is like over 100% usage. People
have multiple cell phones. Um, but you
don't go into the internet these days
and say, "Okay, let me make sure I'm
connecting to the TCP IP layer, right?
It's it's all invisible." And that will
happen with Bitcoin and other
cryptocurrencies. I mean, I see within
the next two years, certainly no more
than five, um, you'll be able to take
out your iPhone and just like right now,
you double click to pay for the stored
credit card that's in there. Instead of
taking it out and typing it in, you just
go double click and it's in there. You
will have your stable coins stored and
accessible to your iPhone. And, you
know, you're not going to put like your
life savings in there, but you might put
5,000, 10,000, $20,000. and Apple will
have insurance, you know, in case that
gets hacked. But, you know, Apple has
been pretty good security just in their
messages. And so, they should be able to
figure out a way to, you know, not have
like, you know, massive hackings of, you
know, smaller amounts of crypto. And as
people get familiar with paying, you
know, when the bill comes paying with
crypto, they're going to find that, oh,
you know what, this particular vendor
says I can pay with credit card and I
get the buyer protection, but I have to
tack on 3.2%. more and more merchants
are doing that. Stable coins, no charge.
And you know, if you're spending $1,000
on something, you're saying, "Do I want
to spend another $32 for the protection
or do I want to just, you know, double
click with my stable coins?" And then
once you have a wallet with stable
coins, I think you're going to find that
people
start looking at having a checking and a
savings account. Their checking account
is stable coins. Their savings account
is Bitcoin.
>> Bitcoin has changed the world. But what
if it could do more than just sit in
your wallet? Welcome to Core Dow, the
largest Bitcoin DeFi ecosystem.
>> Today's sponsor, Core, has over 1
million weekly users, $500 million in
total value locked, and more than 100
live projects. Core is the most advanced
platform for putting your Bitcoin to
work.
>> Core allows you to earn passive yield
with no principal risk. In partnership
with Maple Finance, Core is proud to
introduce LSTBTC
liquid staked Bitcoin.
>> For the first time, Bitcoin holders can
earn sustainable passive yields without
giving up custody or taking up excessive
risk. LSTBTC
transforms Bitcoin into a productive
asset. By time locking your BTC using
proven onchain mechanics, you unlock new
staking rewards while maintaining full
transparency and control. Stake Bitcoin
and Core together to earn even more
thanks to a dynamic dual staking system
that rewards deeper participation. This
is more than DeFi. It's the bridge
between Wall Street and Web 3. LST BTC
is designed to power the next generation
of Bitcoin ETFs, structured financial
products, and institutional-grade
strategies.
>> Bitcoin finally working for you, not
financial advice. Visit cordow.org to
learn more.
>> Um, back to this cycle. Uh we had a
couple Bitcoin miners here yesterday and
I was asking them so there is this
narrative that they have absolute
control over Bitcoin price like you you
were just talking about how if they
don't sell right after having then there
is no supply but they were they were
saying that the first two cycle that
made sense because um Bitcoin mined
every day was a big number but now it
doesn't make sense. Well, it is a
smaller number, but that adds to the
scarcity, right? So, in other words, if
you have more people buying and less
inventory to sell, I think that, you
know, the numbers still make a
difference, right? And so far, the
cycles of fear and greed have continued.
Now, again, that may not be for all 33
cycles. It probably won't be. I think
after the super cycle, you may end up
having a change. I think that as we tend
to be creeping up in the day of the ha
the date of the having because it was I
think the Satoshi planned it to be in US
presidential years
>> and so far it's been that way but it was
November of 2012, July of 2016, May of
2020, April of 2024. At some point if it
keeps on being less than 48 months,
you're going to have it be in the year
prior to the presidential election. And
so that will probably disrupt the fourth
quarter because it would be you know
starting in a prior calendar year and
there's I think there's tax reasons and
a lot of other reasons why you know you
end up having a peak um in the uh end of
a calendar year.
>> But how would that change the cycle?
>> Because if you have an earlier having
you then have an earlier summer and um
when it peaks would probably end up
being um earlier. It just it it's one of
many things that that would sort of
disrupt the way things have been. Um,
and we'll see. I mean, I I think that
we're going to probably still be um
havingings in presidential year
elections for probably at least the next
three cycles because again, the reason
why we moved from like November to July
was because in 2016, we had a lot of
disruption in mining. That's when some
of the Chinese miners shut down and, you
know, moved to Texas and things like
that. And so you had a lot more
disruption you don't do right now
because if we're only moving it up you
know
one month I mean it was like let's see
it was like October September was like
four or five months and then it was like
two months then it's one month and you
know maybe this time it's less than a
month. So we may end up having 2028 I
think right now they're projecting
either late March early April and so the
2032 maybe it's like you know still in
March and and you know the one after
that. So it may be another three, four,
five cycles. You know, five cycles is 20
years.
>> And in 20 years, we will be at over 99%
of the Bitcoin already distributed. And
we will have the scarcity not just a
little bit less than gold, but it's
going to be like what less than.1%.
With a lot more usage. I mean, one of
the analogies that I use is
when you had the S-curve of adoption
happen with cell phones or you had it
with uh the internet, a lot of companies
got really big and rich because they
served the demand of all these new
customers, right? You had like Dell
building laptops, you had Microsoft
making software, you had Cisco making
servers, and it was bull market while
while you're doubling your market share,
right? um you know go from 5% to 10% to
20% of people on on on the internet and
not a lot of competition.
You can't do that with Bitcoin miners.
They can't mine any more than 450 a day.
And they may be able to take a higher
amount of market share, but again that's
only 450 a day. Then it's going to be
225 a day. Then it's going to be 110 a
day. Then it's gonna be 55 a day. You
know, at some point, you know, I mean,
even in the next 20 years, you're going
to be well under 100 a day. And yet the
demand, you know, might be four, five,
six times what it is today. And um you
can't go and just simply say, "Oh, we're
going to build a company to make more
Bitcoin." No more Bitcoin is found
underground. No more Bitcoin is being
found on Mars. It's, you know, the
monetary policy is in code for the next,
you know,und something years, 125 years
or 115 years, 2140. When people say
altcoin season is not coming back this
time, what would you say to them?
>> They don't know what they're talking
about. So, Bitcoin Maxis have for a long
time said yes, all alcoins are are, you
know, frauds and now the gig is up.
They're all going to zero. Ethereum is
going to zero. Salana's going to zero.
It's all going to zero. That's just not
in reality. In fact, it's surprising
that Bitcoin is still at like 64 65%
dominance with the fact that the other
35% includes stable coins. So, stable
coins are a much higher percentage of
the altcoins now and they're going to
continue to grow. Um, and um but you
know, I mean, even meme coins, which
everybody says is going to go to zero,
are still pretty popular. And so,
altcoin season quite interesting. Um,
every cycle you've had new entrance
actually oftentimes not get in Bitcoin
first. They get into altcoins first.
Right. In 2021, um, Robin Hood, a public
company, had, you know, in its quarterly
earnings report that they had a big jump
in their earnings from crypto. 60% of
the crypto traded was Dogecoin.
>> It was more than Ethereum and Bitcoin
and Salana combined.
>> Actually, Salana wasn't anything back
then. Um and so we may see a repeat of
that where you know so far early on you
know a lot of new entrance are in
memecoins are in you know other small
things because a lot of new retail looks
at Bitcoin and say I can't afford
$100,000
>> but I can afford a million of you know
these shebainu coins
>> and you know they're just going to hope
that they go up 100x and you know
sheibba you know is it going to go to a
dollar? Well, if it went to dollar, it'd
be bigger than Bitcoin, right? And I've
worked with the Sheibbao team. Um, and
so I think if people understand that
like particularly if they're younger,
you know, you're 18, 20 years old, you
know, you're probably going to live
another 60 years, maybe 80 years, 100
years if life extension keeps going up.
What's Bitcoin be worth then? Right? So,
if you can go in and figure out how to
get one Bitcoin over the next 10 years,
that could be worth $20 million in, you
know, 20 years, 30 years, certainly by
the time you're retired. And that will
definitely outpace inflation by a lot.
>> Whereas these other things have great
risks.
>> So, when you say altcoin season and
we're in summer, so I would assume that
altcoin season is going to happen soon
because we're in summer,
>> correct? And usually altcoin season um
peaks a little bit after Bitcoin peaks.
>> So in other words um in you know the big
ICO bull market and this last time you
know Bitcoin peaked in December of 2017.
I think Ethereum peaked in like January
or February. Alts pretty much peaked in
other alts peaked in January. And so
usually there's a little bit of a lag
because and again I think institutions
may change this a little bit because
they don't really trade alts. um at
least the smaller ones. So, it's more of
a retail phenomenon, but you know, a lot
of the whales, too. Um and the whales
still control more than the
institutions, right? Um a lot of the
whales will just simply look and say,
"Oh, you know, if they're not perma
holders that never trade, uh they'll
look and say, you know, I've got a great
life. I'm like, you know, I've got like
$100 million of Bitcoin and I don't want
to really sell any, but like I'll take a
little off the top at the end of the
cycle and then buy it back at the
bottom, which is what I advocate." Um,
but a lot of times what they'll do is
they'll go in, um, sell Bitcoin and then
pump an altcoin with that and then sell
that and then, you know, maybe pump a
memecoin at the end of the thing and
then just sit back, hold the cash for a
year and then wait for capitulation,
they buy back in.
>> See, I've heard this theory so many
times, but in reality, it's so hard to
execute.
>> Not really. I mean, I show how to do
that in the book. I mean, you know,
obviously it's better if you have, you
know, an army of algorithmic traders
working with you. And I I do have a fund
called the Bitcoin Super Cycle Genesis
Fund that's uh um you know, going to be
coming to market in a couple weeks.
>> Wow.
>> And um it's for credit investors, but
basically I've got a team of you know,
ALGO programmers that I've worked with
and so they'll go and do algorithmic
programming with within the whole four
years. And there's other companies that
do this, but most uh liquid funds, hedge
funds after fees do not outperform
Bitcoin sitting in your wallet, right?
Because they do it. They take their fees
in cash. They take their percentage in
cash. And if Bitcoin just normally goes
up, you know, you're paying 20% of what
would normally go up. Maybe they're
beating it, but are they beating it by
more than 20% every year, right? And um
so we're looking at beating it by doing
what something almost nobody does, which
is selling almost everything at the top
and then buying it back at the bottom.
>> Wow.
>> So historically,
>> sorry, how would you know if you're at
the top?
>> Again, you look at the calendar, you
look at a number of other things I
discussed in the book, which is like you
look on chain. Yeah.
>> You can see when the whales are selling,
>> you look at um sentiment. There's like
about 20 different factors, but you're
never going to pick the exact day.
Although I have known really good
traders who did pick the exact day and
sold everything on December 17th of
2017. I know two traders that did that
and um other ones that sold, you know,
in early November and picked the day or
within a couple days. But I I recommend
dollar cost averaging out once it gets
into that range where you're like over
90% fear and greed on the greed side
when you can see whales have started to
sell. And so if you dollar cost averaged
out over the last four havingss, I mean,
>> if you went and at the very first
having,
you you you spent $12,700, right? This a
small investment for most investors,
>> beer money, and you you just bought it
and held it forever. You're you have
a,000 Bitcoin today. That $12,000
investment is worth 107 million. Pretty
good investment, right? However, if you
went and held Bitcoin for three years
and held cash for one, so you went and
dollar cost averaged at the top. So, the
first cycle, you would have been able to
divine the the high price over $1,200,
but you would have gotten out around
a,000, right? So, all of a sudden,
you've had your $12 um you know,
Bitcoin. You sold it for a,000 and then
you hold the cash. It dropped all the
way down to 171. You probably weren't
going to buy it that day, but you had
several months afterwards you could have
gotten back in for around 250. So now
all of a sudden you have 4,000 Bitcoin.
You hold that for three years. It went
up to 19,830.
Um, you know, you probably weren't going
to sell on that exact day, although
there was reasons to do that because
that was the day they announced the
futures. Um, it was sell the news. Um,
but you know, you could have pretty
easily gotten out around 16,000 and then
held that cash. It dropped down for a
year. It dropped down to 3,200. Not
saying you would have picked the bottom.
You had several months you could have
gotten in around 4,000. Now you have
16,000 Bitcoin. So basically, you would
have been able to go 4x4x 4x. This last
time a little less than 4x, but you have
about 60,000 Bitcoin. So now your
$12,000 investment isn't worth 107
million. It's worth about five billion.
>> And so by the end of this cycle be
worth, you know, over 10 billion, which
is an extraordinary, you know, return.
Can you tell us about just a little bit
more about the objective of your fund,
the Bitcoin fund that's coming out? Um,
if you believe, if one were to believe
that Bitcoin is going to keep going up
because of these cycles, why not just
buy and hold? Are you trying to
outperform Bitcoin?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. So, that's the Bitcoin. Bitcoin is
basically new market benchmark. It's
like the S&P.
>> Yeah.
>> And you're going to do that by timing
cycles or you going to do that by buying
alts that will outperform Bitcoin as
well?
>> No alts.
>> Okay.
>> Also too risky,
>> right?
Bitcoin is the least risky crypto
investment. It has an almost 0% chance
of going to zero at this point
whereas every alt can go to zero
including Ethereum.
>> If you look at Bitcoin price and it goes
to the range like your prediction,
>> what could tell you we still have a big
way to go or do you just sell then?
>> Well, again, dollar cost averaging and
so um I'm always keeping a little bit of
a moon bag so I probably won't sell
100%. Um because you know you you never
know if this time the cycle might be a
little longer. Last time I probably kept
more than I should have because um there
were there was a big piece of the
narrative that said that a number of you
know pundits and YouTubers were saying
we're going to have an elongated cycle.
It's not going to be a fourth quarter.
It's going to be it's going to be May.
And it wasn't. It was fourth quarter
again.
>> So it's just follow the calendar.
following the calendar but look at the
look at the uh at the metrics you look
at you look on chain um and you look at
you know again five or six things that
that I that I follow to sort of decide
whether it's actually you know repeating
what it's supposed to do
>> well Michael uh tell us about um your
2033 prediction I believe uh you told
the street you had a big rally uh coming
up for us for Bitcoin by 2033 what's
your prediction for the next eight years
out.
>> Sure. So 2029 will be the year after the
next having and I think we'll be around
a half a million.
>> Yeah.
>> And then 2033 is I think when we hit a
million.
>> Okay.
>> Now if we have a super cycle, we could
hit before that. But I I think you'd
have to hit it in the years after the
You're not going to hit it during, you
know, a down year.
>> At what point does Bitcoin overtake gold
in market cap, which is 14 trillion,
>> but that's a moving target, right? So
actually uh gold I think is actually
quite a bit higher than 14 trillion now.
>> Oh yes it is. Yeah that was that was
that was last year.
>> So
>> I think it's almost 20 trillion now.
>> It is it is a million dollars is 20
trillion. Right. So if gold stays around
3500 you need to go to a million. If say
in 8 years gold is 6,000 7,000 certainly
could double by then. Um then you'd have
to be 2 million. Is there a macro case
for Bitcoin to replace gold uh as a de
facto treasury asset not just for
companies but for central banks?
>> Yes. So if you look at you know they had
talked years ago about Ethereum
replacing Bitcoin because they never got
too close but they were heading in that
direction right. So during the ICO craze
of 2017, uh most of it was built on
Ethereum. So people were needing to buy
a lot of Ethereum and Bitcoin went down
to its low point ever in terms of
dominance. It was like around 35%. And
Ethereum was up I think around 20
something percent. So they were saying
they were calling it the flipping
>> when Ethereum uh market cap would flip
Bitcoin and then after that I really
think of Ethereum as the major asset.
Bitcoin would go down, Ethereum would go
up. never came close to happening. I
think you could say the same thing would
be true of gold, right? So, in other
words, if by definition gold is worth
more globally, sorry, Bitcoin is worth
more globally than gold and it's heading
in in the direction of increasing its
lead. I think that you would look and
say, you know, this is, you know, I
think it was uh was it John,
Paul Tudtor Jones that said uh um you
know, Bitcoin's the fastest horse in the
race and he's the guy that really was
the hedge fund that made the most on
gold in the 70s. He's like, "This is the
new gold." And so he's not buying a lot
of gold, he's buying a lot of Bitcoin.
And so I think that if you also look
just generationally, ask your average
25-year-old, if you needed to go and put
half your savings, life savings in gold
or Bitcoin, which would you do?
>> Bitcoin.
>> Exactly. And so those are the people
that are 25 now. At some point, they're
going to be the top earners at 45.
>> Do you think it's always a good time to
buy Bitcoin? No, I think it's not a good
time to buy Bitcoin when the bubble
popped because then you're going to go
and just watch it go down, down, down,
down. That's a good time to short
Bitcoin.
>> Can I just hold it because I know it's
going to come back.
>> You absolutely. In fact, if you hold it,
the good news is that it'll probably be
higher four years later. But if you
didn't buy it and you waited until the
bottom of the market, you know, it's
only a year, you would have been able to
buy two, three, four times as much.
>> Do you generally agree with this general
statement? And last question for me,
churn rate of investors or traders, the
lower it is, the better you are.
>> Could you repeat that one?
>> The churn rate of your of your trades,
>> lower you lower it is, in other words,
the lower the frequency of trading,
generally speaking, the better off
you'll be.
>> Generally speaking, yes. On the other
hand, if you've got good ALOS that
outperform the fees, then you know, I
mean, you know, my fund is going to
trade as much as the ALGO it says to.
It's not gonna be doing 30 trades a day.
It might go a couple days without a
trade, but if it says things are heading
south, it's going to sell.
>> It's not going to sell the whole
portfolio.
>> But for the average investor, who is
>> average investor, you know, the safest
thing if you just don't want to have a
job, you just want to basically just
have something that you think is going
to set it and forget it, buy Bitcoin,
never look at it. And you know, a lot of
people do that and they're going to hand
it over to the grandkids. Mhm.
>> Um, on the other hand, if you want to
work about a couple weeks every four
years, it's not that big of a job,
right? I mean, they say, you know, if
you're a stock market investor, I think
Jim Kramer said you need to spend one
hour per week on each stock you own,
right? That's a lot. And but, you know,
with Bitcoin, you know, literally you
only have to pay attention about like,
you know, twice every four years.
>> A lot of young people watch our show.
Um, some encouragement, maybe they don't
own Bitcoin yet, but anything you want
to say to them? Sure, it's not too late.
I mean, I think it's a given now that
we're going to be at a million dollars.
That means we're only 10 cents on the
dollar where we're going to be in about
eight years. And so, and I show in the
book how you could go in and start with
just one Bitcoin and be close to 100
Bitcoin in like 20 years. And so, if
you're a young person, you got multiple
20-year periods ahead of you.
>> Read the book. Read it.
>> Let's hold this book up. Sure.
Absolutely.
>> Where can we find this book?
>> So, Bitcoin Super Cycle. It's
distributed by Simon and Schustster.
Easiest way to find is on Amazon.
>> Okay. Read this book and follow Michael
Turpin. So that's the uh
>> I'm at Michael Turpin T R P I N on
Twitter.
>> That is the takeaway from this
interview. Thank you so much for coming
to the show. Pleasure.
>> Absolutely.
>> Thank you. Thank you.